<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Evan Matthews</title>
    <link>https://ematth.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Evan Matthews</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ematth.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX for Note-Taking</title>
      <link>https://ematth.dev/note/latex-for-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ematth.dev/note/latex-for-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>$\LaTeX$ LaTeX, pronounced &amp;ldquo;lah-tech&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;lay-tech&amp;rdquo;, is a typesetting system based on the TeX language. It was developed in 1985 by American computer scientist Leslie Lamport, who wrote the package due to his frequent use of shortcuts for mathematical and scientific symbols in his own writing. Since then, it has become a staple in the world of academia as one of the premier document-writing tools with numerous integrations and extensions to the LaTeX package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Made this Website</title>
      <link>https://ematth.dev/note/how-i-made-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ematth.dev/note/how-i-made-this-website/</guid>
      <description>⚠️ This article assumes you have a decent understanding about console commands and Git.
Introduction I have something rather important to get off my chest:
I don&#39;t like web dev. There, I said it. I&#39;ve used plenty of tools in the past, including HTML, CSS and Javascript, yet the idea of making websites never truly stuck. To me, there was always an additional layer of complication that I could never get around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ematth.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ematth.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Evan Matthews is a computer science graduate student at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign. His research focuses primarily on audio computing and AI/ML.
When not programming or doing research, Evan enjoys playing piano and biking.
Education University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign -&amp;gt; 2023-Present M.S. Computer Science Urbana, IL University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign -&amp;gt; 2019-2023 B.S. Computer Science + Music Urbana, IL
Metamora Township High School -&amp;gt; 2015-2019 Metamora, IL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ematth.dev/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ematth.dev/projects/</guid>
      <description>Note: Code for some projects on this list cannot be shared publicly because doing so would be a violation of UIUC&amp;rsquo;s policies on Academic Integrity.
Personal Website Year: May 2023
Tools: HTML, CSS, Markdown, Github Pages
Built with Hugo and designed using the XMIN theme. Read more about my journey through (or around) web development here.
Capstone: Transcribing Monophonic Audio with Deep-Learning Data Year: Spring 2023
Advisor: Zuofu Cheng</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
