<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Evan Matthews</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Evan Matthews</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Playing with 4o Image Generation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/playing-with-4o-image-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/playing-with-4o-image-generation/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s newest image generation model has radically change the landscape of AI-generated images, (for better, or for worse). Admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;ve acted like a &amp;ldquo;kid on Christmas morning&amp;rdquo; for the past two weeks messing around with this model, and I figured what better than to post my use cases and results.&#xA;For the record: this isn&amp;rsquo;t to start some argument about AI art being slop or conflicting with copyright. I&amp;rsquo;m of the opinion that, as much as Image generation trivializes the manual work of drawing/painting art, it&amp;rsquo;s by no means a replacement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSLSC 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025/03/01/cslsc-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025/03/01/cslsc-2025/</guid>
      <description>CSLSC 2025 I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce that CSLSC 2025 was a resounding success! This year, I chaired for the Machine Learning and Signal Processing (MLSP) session alongside Asher Mai. Guest speakers included Dr. Cem Subakan from Université Laval, and Ziyang Chen from the University of Michigan. We also had a handful of student presenters, of which included Trung-Hieu Hoang who won &amp;ldquo;best MLSP student talk.&amp;rdquo; Thank you to everyone who presented and helped in the organization process for the conference, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have done this without you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024/05/20/life-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024/05/20/life-updates/</guid>
      <description>Life updates Wow, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated my blog in a while&amp;hellip;&#xA;My first year of grad school at UIUC has gone and went, and I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished quite a bit since entering the MS CS program last fall.&#xA;I wrote three research papers related to a variety of topics:&#xA;Nearest Neighbor Classication for Classical Image Upsampling with Nic Prate. We wrote this for a class on Machine Learning for Signal Processing in December 2023, and I was very excited to finally get a paper published (and read by other researchers) on arXiv.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cool Python tidbits I enjoy using</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/cool-python-tidbits-i-enjoy-using/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/cool-python-tidbits-i-enjoy-using/</guid>
      <description>Semicolons Languages such as Java and C/C++ used a terminator to indicate the end of a line of code- most often the semicolon ( ; ). While this is not a mandatory feature for Python, you can still use semicolons as line separators. I personally use semicolons to make the most out of horizontal space in my code by combing initialization lines or similar expressions.&#xA;a = 1&#xD;b = 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barbenheimer Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/barbenheimer-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/barbenheimer-review/</guid>
      <description>Barbenheimer Last Friday, I had the pleasure of participating in the Barbenheimer craze, watching Greta Gerwig&amp;rsquo;s Barbie and Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s Oppenheimer. While I don&amp;rsquo;t visit the movie theater often, I found this double feature to be tons of fun, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to give my reviews of both movies in the order that I saw them.&#xA;Barbie I went into Barbie with the understanding that I was certainly not the movie&amp;rsquo;s target audience and that a lot of material wouldn&amp;rsquo;t land with me or any of the other males in the theater.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Fourier Transform The Fourier Transform is a transformation of a time-series function which returns a respective frequency-series function, or an equivalent function who takes a frequency $f$ as an input rather than a time $t$&#xA;$$\hat{f}(\xi) = \int_{-\infty}^{\infty} f(t) e^{-i2\pi\xi t} dt$$&#xA;where $f(t)$ is the original function for our sound in terms of time $t$, and $\hat{f}(\xi)$ is an equivalent function in terms of frequency $\xi$. In essence, this function takes in a frequency and determines that frequency&amp;rsquo;s intensity or usage in a sound across all time values $t$ in $f(t)$- hence why we&amp;rsquo;re integrating with respect to time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplitude</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/amplitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/amplitude/</guid>
      <description>Amplitude The amplitude of a sound is physically defined as the amount of displacement produced by sound waves onto air particles. From the listener&amp;rsquo;s point of view, this variable represents the &amp;ldquo;volume&amp;rdquo; of the sound.&#xA;$$S(t) = A\sin(\omega t + \phi)$$&#xA;Given a sinusoidal function, we define $A$ to be our peak amplitude, or the highest volume that our sound reaches. That is, $\forall t \in \Reals, \space x(t) \in [-A, A] $, (for all inputs $t$, representing time in our sinusoidal function, $x(t)$ will always be between and include $-A$ and $A$).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waveforms and Audio Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/waveforms-and-audio-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/waveforms-and-audio-basics/</guid>
      <description>[[fetch]]&#xD;files = [&#34;./audio1.py&#34;]&#xD;Introduction Understanding the mathematical logic behind sound- how certain factors effect what we hear and how we hear it- is the first step into audio signal processing. You should likely understand some basics about trigonometry and periodic functions to best understand the content. This article will run through basic vocabulary, explain how sound is processed and stored digitally, and demonstrate basic audio processing techniques in Python.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update: Python Compatability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/06/08/update-python-compatability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/06/08/update-python-compatability/</guid>
      <description>[[fetch]]&#xD;files = [&#34;./updatecode.py&#34;, &#34;./reunion.wav&#34;]&#xD;Hey everyone,&#xA;My website now has support for Python code using PyScript! This means that, on top of formatting code for LaTeX formulas&amp;hellip;&#xA;sr1, sample1 = wavread(&#39;./reunion.wav&#39;)&#xD;sample1 = sample1[:int(len(sample1)/4)]&#xD;figure, axs = plt.subplots(1,2)&#xD;figure.set_size_inches(18, 8)&#xD;figure.suptitle(&amp;quot;Chopin Op.28 No. 1 \&amp;quot;Reunion\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)&#xD;axs[0].plot(sample1); axs[0].set_title(&amp;quot;Waveform&amp;quot;)&#xD;a = spectrogram(axs[1], sample1, sr1)&#xD;display(figure, target=&amp;quot;plot&amp;quot;)&#xD;&amp;hellip;my website can now show implementations of formulas and display and plot code output! I hope to start using this feature for my future Audio Processing articles by directly implementing Python code into the page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update: Comments &amp; Future Articles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/06/05/update-comments-future-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/06/05/update-comments-future-articles/</guid>
      <description>💡 You can read the bolded sections of this post to get the TL;DR.&#xA;Hey everyone,&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce that my blog posts now have comments! You can use this section to leave feedback, continue topic discussions or suggest edits. I only ask that everyone be kind and courteous to each other, (please don&amp;rsquo;t force me to moderate negative/toxic comments or remove commenting entirely).&#xA;Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve replaced the previous &amp;ldquo;Articles&amp;rdquo; tab with &amp;ldquo;Audio Processing&amp;rdquo; as I&amp;rsquo;m starting to make audio processing tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX for Note-Taking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/06/03/latex-for-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/06/03/latex-for-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>$\LaTeX$ LaTeX, pronounced &amp;ldquo;lah-tech&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;lay-tech&amp;rdquo;, is a typesetting system based on the TeX language. It was developed in 1985 by American computer scientist Leslie Lamport, who wrote the package due to his frequent use of shortcuts for mathematical and scientific symbols in his own writing. Since then, it has become a staple in the world of academia as one of the premier document-writing tools with numerous integrations and extensions to the LaTeX package.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Made this Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/note/how-i-made-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/note/how-i-made-this-website/</guid>
      <description>⚠️ This article assumes you have a decent understanding about console commands and Git.&#xA;Introduction I have something rather important to get off my chest:&#xA;I don&#39;t like web dev.&#xD;There, I said it. I&#39;ve used plenty of tools in the past, including HTML, CSS and Javascript, yet the idea of making websites never truly stuck. To me, there was always an additional layer of complication that I could never get around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Evan Michael Matthews is a masters student in computer science at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign. His research focuses on audio computing and AI/ML, more specifically the improvement of AI audio generation and lossless translation between sheet music and audio. He is a member of the CS Audio Lab, under thesis advising from Paris Smaragdis and additional research guidance from Minje Kim.&#xA;Evan picked up interests in music when he began learning to play piano and clarinet at age 12.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redirecting...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ssl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/references/</guid>
      <description>Global JOS Index&#xA;Smith, J.O. Mathematics of the Discrete Fourier Transform (DFT) with Audio Applications, Second Edition, http://ccrma.stanford.edu/~jos/mdft/, online book, 2007 edition, accessed from 07/03/2023 to present date.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
